Jai Hind friends, today I am going to tell you
that if you take a loan, any kind
of loan, then you may have to face income tax.
You may get an income
tax notice. Many people have
received such a notice and they are
reading today how to respond to it, even though their income is not very
high, but still they are getting a
notice. Now I am going to
tell you why this is happening. If you are ever going to take a loan, be it a
business loan, personal
loan, home loan, any kind of loan, if you are going to
take a loan or have already taken it, then
forget it, but if you are going to take it or are
planning to take it in the future, then you
must watch this video completely. I will
give all the information in a very short time. Before proceeding further, I
would request you to like the video. If you have
any question,
write in the comment box and I will make a video on your topic.
For your information, let me tell you that whenever
you take a loan of any kind, then many
types of documents are required. Some documents are
very compulsory, they are required in every loan,
like I told you, Aadhar  Card
is required in all loans, PAN card
is required in all loans, 6 months bank statement
is required in all loans, apart from this if it is a
business loan then you need GST
registration certificate, apart from this
MSME certificate is required, apart from this I
tell you that if you are taking a housing loan
then you need property
papers, if you want to take a personal loan then salary
slip is required, now I tell you that the
process is different in all but one process is that
which is required in all and that is compulsory,
like I told you Aadhar card, PAN card,
bank statement, leave aside Aadhar PAN, everyone has
relief, there is a bank statement, this is the
matter in most of the institutions, what happens here is a
bank account, you show the transactions in your bank, if
your transactions are good in 6 months then only you will
get the loan, now what we do is those who have less
income, less transactions or those who earn
income in some way, be it
from business or salary, then they start transacting
other's money to show transactions in the account, they
think they want to
take a loan, so they start depositing other's money,
now if they have 5  If you want to
take a loan of even one lakh, you want to take a loan of eight lakhs, even two lakhs, then what do you do? You make a
transaction of 25 lakhs, 30 lakhs in 6 months by investing
other's money and asking for money from others,
asking for money from friends, but
they do not know that this is going to prove to be very harmful
for them. Now coming to the case of
businessmen, if a business is
taking a loan, then they also
show transactions of crores in 6 months. Now
where does the matter get stuck? You have shown this, if the
loan is sanctioned and you also got the loan, did you face
any problem? When did the problem arise?
When you file the ITR later, you have to
file ITR somehow, you have
taken a loan and are earning income, so
when you file ITR or
in some loans, you are asked for 2
years' ITR, you give it, in some loans,
ITR is not asked also, but
when you file the next ITR, then the
money that you will show as income in it, that my annual
income is business and somehow,
how many years' income is ₹1.5 lakh  If you have ₹2 lakh, 2.5
lakh, 3 lakh, but
you are seeing transactions of ₹25 lakh or 30 lakh in 6 months, then
what will the bank do? It will
send your report to the Income Tax Department.
First of all, it sends it like this in someone's
account. If there is a
cash transaction of more than ₹10 lakh in a year in a savings account, or if there is an
online transaction of more than ₹20 lakh, then
that report is definitely sent
to the Income Tax Department, but you do
not get a notice because when you file the ITR, if
both match then you do
not get a notice. If there is some kind of up and down, then you do
not get a notice.
But here the case will be that there is a
transaction of ₹30-35 lakh in your account. You have taken
so much tension to take a loan of ₹5 lakh
from other people's money and are filing ITR for ₹
5 lakh annually, ₹6 lakh annually, ₹
7 lakh annually. Now what will happen, the Income Tax
Department will send you a notice as soon as the bank
gives its information. Their chairman  The
department will send you a notice that
your loan is done, it will be known later that
you have to pay a penalty, when the penalty has to be paid,
when it is proved that the money is
yours, now accept it, you will say that the money is
not mine, then you prove it, how will you prove it,
you have to prove it, you have to prove it, if there is
any confusion in your answer if you cannot prove it,
then the
income tax department is late with you in the form of 200% penalty, such
notices have
come to you recently from many people, many people had taken business loans,
what happened to them, they took business loans, they
showed transactions of a lot of crores, what
happened now is that when they are filing GST, they are
showing less in that too, they are showing less in
filing their income tax returns,
and it is being found that
transactions on the accounts are current accounts, everyone's
accounts are going to crores in a year, just
for the role, they took money from some places and did
transactions, now the matching did not happen,
later it was found out that brother, this was found to be
fake, now when they could not respond, everyone got a
notice and the same thing happened with everyone
that everyone had to pay the penalty  Many
people will have to pay so much penalty that
even their business will be shut down, so friends, I
say that just to get a loan, do not
transact someone else's money on your account,
yes do the transaction, now
if your salary is 20000, 25000, 30 thousand, you are
transacting your money, what is the
problem, transact your money accordingly, do the transaction, there is
no problem, it fluctuates a little, let me
tell you that even if your salary is ₹ 20, 25000, you
can still get Rs 10 lakh, 8 lakh, 7 lakh, 47, let me
tell you that even if your salary is ₹ 10, 15, 20 thousand,
you can still get a loan of 2 lakh to 5 lakh rupees, even then
you can get a loan on 10 lakh, 15 lakh,
then what is the use of showing someone else's transaction,
go according to your income,
replace option
is business,
take a loan according to your transaction, you will get it easily, why will we take it
in crores, why will we take it for 50
Why would we take a loan of Rs. 10 lakhs? Take a loan of Rs. 10 crores.
You must
show the transactions accordingly so that your business does
not face any difference. Whether you are taking a business loan, a home
loan or a personal loan, there should
not be any problem. The
ITR you are filing, your
salary and your bank balance should match.
If you take a little bit, a little
bit means even up to ₹1 lakh is up or down, then
it can be managed. But
here, if there is a gap of 20 lakhs, 25 lakhs, 15 lakhs, 10 lakhs, then there
is so much gapping in the account, there is so much gapping in the ITR,
then the Income Tax department will
not leave you because the bank always reports, it does
not report for everyone with more transactions. Today the notice came after 2 years,
after 4 years, there are many such cases.
I am telling you about myself. I myself got a notice
after a year. I am telling you about one time, the notice came
after 4 years. It was in 2017,
I filed my ITR in 2017.  I did it
and what happened at that time was that
according to GG, I had income and there was a lot of land
transaction, a lot of
transactions, I did not expect that the bank
also reports it, a lot of transactions,
approximately 55 lakhs had happened since 1950,
which was not my own
money, there was very little that I was doing on my
transactions, in which
money used to come from outside, from others, I used to
give money to someone else, so this was the kind of
transaction and what happened was that I got a
notice from the Income Tax Department, now I got a
notification from the Income Tax Department,
I had to pay the tax, the
notice said that brother,
you have to pay so much money, your
income is so much, they asked for an answer, along with the answer, I
also paid their money, I did
not have to pay any penalty, but now if you ignore it again and again, there is a
penalty, there is a penalty up to 2%,
first of all you should correct this thing that do
not do any kind of fake transaction to get a loan.  Do original transactions, do
more transactions with your own money, even
if you are doing more, then
keep a record of where the money came from, where it went, you
can transfer the money of your family members, you can take
care of your loved ones,
but do
not create a burden by transacting the money of your friends, relatives or anyone else, it will get
stuck in this way, that is why I am
telling you that many people
take loans and do such things and
later they may have to face problems.